Finding Aid for the Douglas Ainslie Letters LSC.0703
UCLA Library Special Collections
Douglas Ainslie Letters
1884-1931
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ainslie, Douglas
LSC.0703
1.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Grant Duff Douglas Ainslie (1865-1948) was an English poet, critic, and diplomat. He translated works of Benedetto Croce into English and wrote Chosen Poems (1928) and The Conquest of Pleasure (1942). The collection consists of correspondence to Douglas Ainslie from various persons including one letter from Ainslie to Constance Wilde.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994621533606533
Biography
Grant Duff Douglas Ainslie was born in Paris, France in 1865; BA, Oxford, 1886; became an English poet, critic, and diplomat; translated works of Benedetto Croce into English; publications include Chosen Poems (1928) and The Conquest of Pleasure (1942); died March 27, 1948.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence to Douglas Ainslie from various persons. Includes one letter from Ainslie to Constance Wilde.
General note
List of Correspondents
Organization and Arrangement
Collection arranged alphabetically.
Letters.; Authors, English -- Correspondence.; Ainslie, Douglas, 1865-1948--Correspondence.
- Adey, More., 1 item.
- Ainley, Henry Hinchliffe, 1879-1945., 1 item.
- Alexander, Sir George, 1858-1918., 6 items (folder).
- Archer, William, 1856-1924., 1 item.
- Baylis, Lilian Mary, d. 1937., 1 item.
- Bealby, Mabel (Beardsley)., 2 items (folder).
- Berenson, Bernhard, 1865-1959., 3 items (folder).
- Binyon, Laurence, 1869-1943., 1 item.
- Bourchier, Arthur, 1863-1927., 33 items (folder).
- Brown, William Sorley, 1889-., 1 item.
- Campbell, Mrs. Patrick, 1865-1940., 1 item.
- Cholmondeley, Mary, 1859-1925., 3 items (folder).
- Clerk, Sir George Russell, 1874-1951., 1 item.
- Cocks, Philip Alphonso Somers, 1862-1940., 6 items (folder).
- Coffin, Charles Hayden, 1862-1935., 2 items (folder).
- Cole, Horace de Vere., 1 item.
- Collins, John Churton, 1848-1908., 9 items (folder).
- Colvin, Sir Sidney, 1845-1927., 1 item.
- Conder, Charles, 1868-1909., (folder)
- Cust, Henry John Cockayne, 1861-1925., 2 items (folder).
- Cutler, Kate, 1870-., 1 item.
- D'Arcy, Ella., 1 item.
- Dare, Phyllis, 1890-., 21 items (folder).
- Dare, Zena, 1887-., 6 items (folder).
- Douglas, Olive Eleanor (Custance) Lady Alfred Douglas, 1874-., 1 item.
- Duclaux, Mme. Agnes Mary Frances (Robinson) 1857-., 1 item.
- Du Maurier, Sir Gerald, 1873-1934., 2 items (folder).
- Edwardes, George, 1855-1915., 2 items (folder).
- Elliott, Maxine, 1871-1940., 5 items (folder).
- Forbes-Robertson, Sir Johnston, 1853-1937., 4 items (folder).
- Forbes-Robertson, May Gertrude Elliott (Dermot) lady, 1874-., 1 item (folder).
- Forbes-Robertson, Norman, 1858-., 6 items (folder).
- Garvice, Charles, d. 1920., 1 item.
- Glyn, Mrs. Elinor (Sutherland)., 1 item.
- Grey, Sybil., 2 items (folder).
- Hackney, Mabel., 5 items (folder).
- Hamlyn, Vincent Waldo Calmady., 1 item.
- Hand, Sarah Chapman., 3 items (folder).
- Hardwicke, Albert Edward Philip Henry Yorke, 6th Earl of, 1867-1904., 2 items (folder).
- Hare, Augustus John Cuthbert, 1834-1903., 2 items (folder).
- Hargrave, John, 1894-., 1 item.
- Headlam, Stewart Duckworth, 1847-1924., 3 items (folder).
- Hecht, Henry., 1 item (folder).
- Hecht, Max., 2 items (folder).
- Heinemann, William, 1863-1920., 1 item.
- Herbert, Arthur Frederick, 1866-1907., 10 items (folder).
- Herbert, Victoria., 1 item.
- Hichens, Robert Smythe, 1864-1950., 3 items (folder).
- Hicks, Sir Edward Seymour, 1871-1949., 2 items.
- Holmes, Thomas, 1846-1918., 3 items (folder).
- Hood, Hon. Alexander Nelson, Duke of Bronte, 1854-1937., 6 items (folder).
- Horner, Frances (Graham) Lady., 5 items (folder).
- Irving, Sir Henry, 1838-1905., 7 items (folder).
- Jackson, Holbrook, 1874-1948., 1 item.
- Jerningham, Charles Edward Wynne, 1854-1921., 35 items (folder).
- Lang, Alexander Matheson, 1879-1948., 1 item.
- Langtry, Lillie, 1852-1929., 2 items (folder).
- Lee, Sir Sidney, 1859-1926., 1 item.
- Lewis, Wyndham, 1886-1957., 1 item.
- Ludovici, Anthony Mario, 1882-., 2 items (folder).
- Maude, Cyril, 1862-., 1 item.
- Menpes, Mortimer, 1859-1938., 26 items (folder).
- Merivale, Herman Charles, 1839-1906., 2 items (folder).
- Nesbit, Evelyn., 1 item.
- Orpen, Sir William, 1878-1931., 3 items (folder).
- Plarr, Victor Gustave, 1863-1929., 1 item.
- Playfair, Sir Nigel Ross, 1874-1934., 1 item.
- Poel, William, 1852-1934., 3 items.
- Ridge, William Pett, d. 1930., 3 items.
- Robertson, Walford Graham, 1867-1948., 1 item.
- Robins, Elizabeth, 1862-1952., 14 items (folder).
- Ronald, Sir Landon, 1873-1938., 1 item (folder).
- Rumbold, Sir Horace, bart., 1869-1941., 1 item.
- Sayle, Charles Edward, 1864-1924., 2 items (folder).
- Shannon, Charles Hazelwood, 1865-1937., 1 item.
- Sharp, Evelyn, 1869-., 3 items (folder).
- Sickert, Walter, 1860-1942., 2 items (folder).
- Sindici, Magda., 1 item.
- Straus, Ralph, 1882-., 3 items (folder).
- Studholme, Marie, 1875-., 4 items (folder).
- Sultan Muhammond Shah, agha khan, 1877-., 4 items (folder).
- Symons, Arthur, 1865-1945., 1 item.
- Tempest, Dame Marie Susan, 1866-1942., 2 items (folder).
- Terriss, Ellaline, 1871-., 1 item.
- Terry, Marion, 1856-1930., 2 items.
- Toynbee, William, 1849-., 35 items (folder).
- Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, 1852-1917., 9 items (folder).
- Vanbrugh, Dame Irene, 1872-1949., 14 items (folder).
- Vanbrugh, Violet, 1867-1942., 10 items (folder).
- Watts-Dunton, Theodore, 1832-1914., 2 items (folder).
- Wyndham, Sir Charles, 1837-1919., 4 items (folder).